<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eliezer de Souza da Silva</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Eliezer de Souza da Silva</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>Bio #I am Eliezer de Souza da Silva, a postdoctoral researcher specializing in Data Science, Machine Learning, Generative Models, and Causality. Currently, I am working at the Fundação Getúlio Vargas (FGV) School of Applied Mathematics in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/research/</guid>
      <description>Scientific knowledge is built on the foundations of probabilistic thinking, aiming to understand not only the associations between events but also how one event influences the occurrence of another.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing GFlowNets: Stability, Expressiveness, and Assessment</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publications/2024a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publications/2024a/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Generative Flow Networks (GFlowNets) are powerful samplers for distributions over compositional objects (e.g., graphs). In this work, we analyze GFlowNets from three fundamental perspectives: stability, expressiveness, and assessment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human-in-the-Loop Causal Discovery under Latent Confounding using Ancestral GFlowNets</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publications/2023a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publications/2023a/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Structure learning is the crux of causal inference. Notably, causal discovery (CD) algorithms are brittle when data is scarce, possibly inferring imprecise causal relations that contradict expert knowledge &amp;ndash; especially when considering latent confounders.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prior Specification for Bayesian Matrix Factorization via Prior Predictive Matching</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publications/2023b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publications/2023b/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The behavior of many Bayesian models used in machine learning critically depends on the choice of prior distributions, controlled by some hyperparameters typically selected through Bayesian optimization or cross-validation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time is of the Essence: a Joint Hierarchical RNN and Point Process Model for Time and Item Predictions</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publications/2019a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publications/2019a/</guid>
      <description>Abstract In recent years session-based recommendation has emerged as an increasingly applicable type of recommendation. As sessions consist of sequences of events, this type of recommendation is a natural fit for Recurrent Neural Networks (RNNs).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Content-Based Social Recommendation with Poisson Matrix Factorization</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publications/2017a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publications/2017a/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We introduce Poisson Matrix Factorization with Content and Social trust information (PoissonMF-CS), a latent variable probabilistic model for recommender systems with the objective of jointly modeling social trust, item content and user’s preference using Poisson matrix factorization framework.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(test post) Sampling from Dirichlet Distribution using Gamma Distributed Samples</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/old1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/old1/</guid>
      <description>There is an algorithm to generate Dirichlet samples using a sampler for Gamma distribution for any \( \alpha &amp;gt; 0 \) and \( \beta &amp;gt; 0 \).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large-scale distributed locality-sensitive hashing for general metric data</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publications/2014a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publications/2014a/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Locality-Sensitive Hashing (LSH) is extremely competitive for similarity search, but works under the assumption of uniform access cost to the data, and for just a handful of dissimilarities for which locality-sensitive families are available.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/people/</guid>
      <description>Johasdn Doe Cute Cat&#xA;Jane Smith Cute Cat&#xA;Jane Smith Cute Cat&#xA;Jane Smith Cute Cat&#xA;Jane Smith Cute Cat&#xA;Jane Smith Cute Cat</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
